thrivent.com 2008-09-27

# Thrivent Financial for Lutherans

Thank you for taking the time to view this policy. Thrivent Financial values your business and is committed to safeguarding the information you provide to us online. We do not share or exchange information gathered on this site with outside organizations who are not performing services for us or on our behalf. Please review this policy to help you better understand our views and practices regarding privacy on our Web site. 

  * What information do we gather on our Web site?
  * What other information do we capture?
  * How do we protect your personal information?
  * How can you update the personal information you provide online?
  * What do we do with the information we gather?
  * How do you opt in/out of receiving e-mails about updates to our Web site?
  * How do you opt out of data sharing and e-mail marketing?
  * Do we use cookie technology?
  * How can you set or delete your computer’s cookies?
  * Do we use Web beacons?
  * Do we use P3P technology?
  * Do we use encryption technology?
  * What is our policy for children?
  * What about links to other Web sites from Thrivent Financial's site?
  * Questions or comments?

Top of page

**What information do we gather on our Web site?**  
When you register for Lutherans Online chat rooms and message boards or other free Lutherans Online services we ask that you provide your name, date of birth, e-mail address, and postal address (including city, state, and ZIP code). 

For added security, to register for access to My Accounts or Members/Chapters areas, you will need to provide the above listed information plus your Social Security number or Thrivent ID, and contract number or birth date. This information, required at initial registration only, is used to identify you as a unique, authorized user. 

**Thrivent Financial will never ask you to provide or confirm your personal information through an e-mail unless you have requested such an e-mail or transaction from us. Never respond to an e-mail (especially[unsolicited e-mail](http://www.thrivent.com/phishing.html)) which asks for personal or account information.**

In other sections of our Web site (e.g., information request forms, financial questionnaires, order forms, etc.), we may capture additional information you may supply including personal financial information, telephone number, name of your church, the home city/state of your church, whether or not you are Lutheran, and other personal information in order to fulfill your request. 

Top of page

**What other information do we capture?**  
Thrivent Financial's Web server automatically recognizes your IP address when you visit our site as an anonymous visitor (without logging in). It does not recognize your e-mail address. However, we do collect your e-mail address if you communicate with us via e-mail or provide your e-mail address to us when completing an online survey or registering for various sections of our site. 

If you register on our site, please keep your personal information, including your e-mail address, up to date by following the instructions below. This e-mail address will be used by you to retrieve a forgotten password and assist you in using other self-service features. 

Thrivent Financial collects aggregate information about the pages visited within our Web site. We also capture browser type and version, and screen resolution. This information will assist us in providing a more user-friendly site and to aid in problem resolution if you experience technical difficulties while visiting our site. 

If you access or service your accounts online using your user ID and password to authenticate yourself, a record of your online activity is maintained. 

Top of page

**How can you update the personal information you provide online?**  
My Accounts, Members/Chapters and Lutherans Online registration – You can change the information you provided at registration, including your current e-mail address, through your online personal profile. To update your profile: 

  1. Log in to a secure area, and click on **Manage my Profile**. 
  2. Click the link for the information category you would like to update. 
  3. Update and verify your personal information as desired. If indicated on your personal profile screen, you may need to click the Name & Address Change Request form link to change some of your information. Note: Your User ID cannot be changed. 
  4. Save your changes. The information in your personal profile will be updated. 

ThriveQ registration – You can change the information you provided at registration, including your current e-mail address, through My Account. To update your information: 
  1. Log in to ThriveQ.com and click on **My Account**.
  2. Update and verify your personal information as desired.
  3. Click **Update** to save your changes.

Top of page

**How do we protect your personal information?**  
We have strict standards of security to safeguard your data. In fact, the physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in place to protect your data often exceed regulatory requirements. The technology we use to protect your data is reviewed often. We improve the process as needed. 

Only authorized employees and representatives may access and use data about you. All are trained to safeguard your data. Those who use your data must follow established standards, procedures and laws. Also, Thrivent Financial uses encryption technology when sending or requesting personal information via the Internet. 

Top of page

**What do we do with the information we gather?**  
We use the information we gather about our site visitors in one or more of the following ways: 

  * To verify your Thrivent Financial membership status and/or account ownership. 
  * To fulfill orders and requests for additional information. 
  * To fulfill your requests for contact from a Thrivent Financial representative. 
  * To help ensure a safer online environment for our site visitors. 
  * For general aggregate site visitor analysis and statistical research.
  * To increase visitor satisfaction in their online experience with Thrivent Financial. 
  * To inform customer service professionals or financial representatives about account access and service requests that will enable us to provide you with better customer service. 
  * To inform you of updates to our Web site (if you request it in your personal profile, during or after registration). 
  * To provide you with information about products and services available through Thrivent Financial and/or its affiliated companies that may be of interest to you. You can opt out of receiving this information during or after registering for the site.
  * To help resolve disputes, if needed.
  * To provide you with security information to assist you in accessing our Web site.

Top of page

**How do you opt in/out of receiving e-mails about updates to our Web site?**  
To change your preference for receiving updates to our Web site, you need to update your personal profile. To do this: 

  1. Log in to a secure area, and click on **Manage my Profile**. 
  2. Click **Access Areas**. 
  3. Check/uncheck the **Send Me Updates** check box.
  4. Click **Continue** to save your changes. The information in your online personal profile will be updated. 

Top of page

**How do you opt out of data sharing and e-mail marketing?**  
To opt out of data sharing and e-mail marketing, call us toll-free at 800-701-3885. We are available to answer calls between the hours of 7 a.m. and 9 p.m. Central time Monday through Friday and between the hours of 9 a.m. and 1 p.m. Central time on Saturday. You may select one or more of the following options: 

  * Tell us not to share data about you within our family of companies. However, we may still share transactional and experiential data including the existence of your products, services or benefits; and data about you as needed by our fraternal operations.  

  * Direct us not to share data about you with other financial institutions with which we have joint marketing agreements. We do not share or exchange information gathered on this site with outside organizations who are not performing services for us or on our behalf.  

  * Request we remove your name from some or all of our internal marketing lists. You should know that our regular service mailings may still contain marketing materials. If you have opted in to receive electronic service notifications and/or confirmations, you will continue to receive such e-mails.  

  * In all states, except California, Minnesota, New Mexico, North Dakota and Vermont, tell us not to share data about you with nonprofit Lutheran organizations. In California, Minnesota, New Mexico, North Dakota and Vermont, we do not share data about you with nonprofit Lutheran organizations.. 

Top of page

**Do we use cookie technology?**  
Cookies are messages which often include anonymous unique identifiers given to your Web browser by a Web server. The browser stores the message on your computer. The message is sent back to the server each time your browser requests that site. For security reasons, cookies are not used for automatic access to secure areas on Thrivent Financial's Web sites. You need to type your user ID and password every time you log in to a secure access area. 

Cookie technology, however, may be used in various sections of our Web site to provide you with customized services and increase the quality of your online experience. Thrivent Financial may use cookies to create a unique identifier to recognize you as a repeat visitor on subsequent visits. The cookie uses this identifier to differentiate site visitors, it does not provide any personal identifying information. 

Cookies: 

  * Can NOT be used to reveal your e-mail address obtained from your hard drive or learn confidential or personal information about you that you have not already explicitly revealed.  

  * Can NOT read data off your hard drive or read cookie files created by other sites.   

  * Are NOT executable programs and can NOT damage your computer or files on your computer. 

Top of page

**How can you set or delete your computer’s cookies?**  
You can set your computer’s browser to opt-out of receiving and storing cookies, however, doing so may limit your access to certain sections of our site. You also can delete cookies stored on your computer’s browser. The process to set or delete cookies differs by browser. See your browser’s Help feature or contact the manufacturer for instructions on how to set/delete your browser’s cookie options. Below are instructions for the more popular browsers. 

> **To delete cookies in Microsoft Internet Explorer:**
> 
>   1. Click Tools, then Internet Options.
>   2. Click the Delete Cookies button (under Temporary Internet Files box) and OK to confirm.
>   3. Click OK to close the Internet Options box.
> 

> 
> **To delete cookies in Mozilla Firefox:**
> 
>   1. Click Tools, then Clear Private Data.
>   2. Be sure the Cookies box is checked, then click Clear Private Data Now.
> 

> 
> **To delete cookies in Apple Safari:**
> 
>   1. Click Edit, then Preferences.
>   2. Click the Security tab.
>   3. Click the Show Cookies button.
>   4. Click the Remove All button.
> 

Top of page

**Do we use Web beacons?**  
Web beacons (also known as Web bugs, pixel/page tags and clear GIFs) are used with cookies to monitor the behavior of site visitors based on IP address. Thrivent Financial uses Web beacons on its Web sites and in e-mail communications for aggregate statistical purposes. 

Top of page

**Do we use P3P technology?**  
Thrivent Financial uses P3P technology. P3P (Platform for Privacy Preferences) allows you to monitor and control the way your personal information is used on Web sites. If you have a P3P-enabled browser, you can set specific privacy criteria that you are comfortable with. Then, when you visit a Web site that has summarized their privacy practices for P3P, your browser will evaluate the site to see if it meets your criteria. Sites not matching your criteria will result in the browser displaying a warning notice or blocking transmission to the site. 

Top of page

**Do we use encryption technology?**  
Several areas on Thrivent Financial's Web site (e.g., My Accounts) have been built to handle sensitive or confidential information. These pages utilize an Internet method known as Secure Socket Layers (SSL). With SSL engaged, pages are sent to you in an encrypted (scrambled) format and any information you submit to Thrivent Financial also is encrypted. Encryption is the transformation of data into a form unreadable by anyone who doesn't have the appropriate decryption key. This method of transferring sensitive data is considered the industry standard for the Internet. 

For added security, close your browser completely when you finish using this site. While online, your browser is using part of your computer's memory. If your broswer is left open, it may be possible for someone using your computer to go back and use this memory to access your information. Closing your browser, clears this memory. You may also want to consider clearing your browser's temporary files. 

For your security, we highly recommend you update your browser to versions that support SSL. Microsoft Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox and Apple Safari are three browsers that support these encryption techniques. A solid lock graphic will display when the SSL mode is engaged and the connection is encrypted. If you are not sure if your browser is compatible, check with your service provider. 

Thrivent Financial has taken steps to make all information you provide to us as secure as possible against unauthorized access and use, alteration, and/or loss. This information is kept in Thrivent Financial's secure database. You should keep in mind, however, that no data transmission over the Internet is 100 percent secure and any information disclosed online can potentially be intercepted and used by unauthorized parties. 

Top of page

**What is our policy for children (individuals under 13 years of age)?**  
Your children's safety is important to us! We have developed our privacy guidelines in compliance with the requirements outlined by the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). No information should be submitted to or posted on our site by children under 13 years of age without the consent of their parent or guardian. Registration will not be accepted if the birth date indicates the individual is under the age of 13. 

Top of page

**What about links to other Web sites from Thrivent Financial's site?**  
The Thrivent Financial Web site contains links to several other Internet sites. Although our intent is to provide links to other quality sites, we cannot guarantee the safety and privacy of information you provide to these linked sites. Any data or personal information collected by Web sites other than Thrivent Financial for Lutherans are not covered by this privacy policy. 

Top of page

**Questions or comments?**  
If you have questions regarding our Internet Privacy Policy, send an e-mail message to [mail@thrivent.com](mailto:mail@thrivent.com), or send your written request to Thrivent Financial for Lutherans, 4321 N. Ballard Rd., Appleton, WI 54919. 

Also, if you receive e-mail messages from Thrivent Financial about updates to our Web site and wish to no longer receive these updates, you can unsubscribe from our mailing list following the unsubscribe directions in the e-mail. You also can unsubscribe by updating your personal profile (under Manage My Profile). 

Notice of any material change to our Internet Privacy Policy is given on the thrivent.com home page. 

This Internet Privacy Policy and any updates are effective as of June 10, 2008.   
Top of page
